# MinJoo Cho

### **Creative Interaction Technologist**



**ADDRESS** Schultzweg 2, Hamburg, 20097,

Germany

**EMAIL** minjoolisa.cho@gmail.com

NATIONALITY South Korean (EU Blue card holder) PHONE +49-174-6231773

DATE / PLACE OF

1987-06-30 / Seoul

LINKS Personal Webpage, LinkedIn

#### **Profile**

Minjoo Cho has graduated from M.S in Industrial Design from KAIST(Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, South Korea) where she has received her B.S in Electrical Engineering.

Through her studies, she participated in various interactive projects: Calm Automaton(A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Display), Ratchair (Furniture That Learns to Move Itself). Prior to her graduate school, she was a project member of Samsung Creative Lab(C-Lab) for Touch Music project that aimed to provide multi-sensory music player for the deaf, followed by her project management experience in Samsung Galaxy Tablet series and Google Nexus 10 at Samsung Electronics for 3 years.

Currently, she joined INDEED Innovation GmbH as a Creative Interaction Technologist. Her main interest resides in reaching and combining ideas from different fields including Design, Technology, and Art embraced with Humanity where she always believes in.

# **Employment History**

May 2017 - Present

HAMBURG AREA, GERMANY

### **Creative Interaction Technologist**

Indeed Innovation GmbH

As a creative interaction technologist, I explore opportunities to introduce new IoT systems (or product) to clients or share experiences/opinions towards the future and technological advance to the public. My current BI Music Installation, Brain Composer, was exhibited at the House of Beautiful Business, Lisbon in 2019.

Jun 2013 - Oct 2014 SUWON, SOUTH KOREA Creative Lab

Samsung Electronics

A developer/program planner of an interdisciplinary project in Samsung Electronics. Designed a multi-modal sound visualisation tool for the deaf.

http://www.minjoolisacho.net/portfolio/gallery-c-lab.html

Jan 2011 - Dec 2014 SUWON, SOUTH KOREA **Production Manager** Samsung Electronics

A product manager of Samsung Tablets throughout the whole product life cycle from product planning stage to the end of the production. I was responsible for Nexus 10, a collaborative project with Google HQ, and a manger of two Samsung tablet projects (GALAXY Note10.1, GALAXY Tab3 10.1) to successfully launch them to the global market.

## **Internships**

Oct 2009 — Feb 2010 KYOTO, JAPAN

### Research Intern

ATR(Advanced Telecommunications Research Institute)

Human-Robot Verbal Interaction: Participated in the early development stage of a listener robot for verbal communication with human specialised for teleoperation environment.

Aug 2009 — Oct 2009 TOKYO, JAPAN

#### Research Intern

Toshiba

Human-Robot Verbal Interaction Human-Robot Nonverbal Interaction: Development of a visualisation tool to display "Interest Rate" read the Robot as a response to the visual input from the user.

#### **Education**

Mar 2015 — Feb 2017 DAEJEON, SOUTH KOREA

# Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Master of Science in Industrial Design

Majored in Industrial Design, myDesignLAB. My major research interest is in introducing interactive DIY tools to invite general users (without technological knowledge) to actively participate in the design process.

The graduation project, Calm Automaton, was a DIY toolkit for ambient displays and was demonstrated in CHI 2017 (Conference on Human Factors in Computing System).

Mar 2006 — Feb 2011 DAEJEON, SOUTH KOREA

## Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Major - Electrical Engineering, Minor - Business Economics

#### **Courses**

Nov 2018 - Jan 2019

**Machine Learning** 

Coursera

Languages	Korean English Japanese	••••	Chinese German	•••••
Skills	Prototyping (Processing, Arduino, Raspberry Pi)	••••	Web development basics (P5.js, html, css, node.js)	••••
	Computer Vision (Unity 3D, Processing, Open CV, Python)	••••	Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, After Effects)	••••
	Digital Fabrication : 3D Modeling (Rhinoseros, Fusion 360, Inventor) /	••••	Rendering (Keyshot 5)  MS Office (PowerPoint / Excel)	••••
	Machine Learning	• • • • •	Exectly	
	Computer Language (C, C#,	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$		

# **Interactive Projects & Publications**

Mar 2019 — Jun 2019	Brain Composer
---------------------	----------------

Java)

**HAMBURG** 

This project explores the possibility of the brain interface to create Al-driven music applications.

Nov 2017 — Nov 2017

HAMBURG

### How Will Al Change You

How Will Al Change You, gives participants an opportunity to be "The Thinker", reflecting on personal and collective futures with intelligent machines.

May 2017 — May 2017 COLORADO

# Calm Automaton : A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays

Minjoo Cho and Daniel Saakes. 2017. Calm Automaton: A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays. In *Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI EA '17). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 393-396. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/2027063.2052069

https://doi.org/10.1145/3027063.3052968

Aug 2016 — Aug 2016 ANAHEIM

#### Ratchair: furniture learns to move itself with vibration.

Tetiana Parshakova, Minjoo Cho, Alvaro Cassinelli, and Daniel Saakes. 2016. Ratchair: furniture learns to move itself with vibration. In *ACM SIGGRAPH 2016 Emerging Technologies* (SIGGRAPH '16). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 19, 2 pages. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/2929464.2929473

Sep 2015 — Sep 2015 KWANGJU

### Sketching in virtual reality for rapid and situated idea generation

Cho, MJ., Lee, B, Min, J., Saakes, D.P. Sketching in virtual reality for rapid and situated idea generation In KSDS Fall Conference 2015.

Apr 2009 — Apr 2009 DAEJEON

### Animal Robot Interaction for PetCaring

Seung-Hwan Choi, Duckhwan Kim, Joonwoo Kim, Minjoo Cho, "Animal Robot Interaction for PetCaring", Computational Intelligence in Robotics and Automation (CIRA), 2009

### Talks & Workshop

Jul 2019 — Jul 2019

HAMBURG

Job Talk, Forward Festival

https://page-online.de/branche-karriere/page-auf-dem-forward-festival-in-hamburg/

Feb 2019 - Feb 2019

**HAMBURG** 

Woman in Tech Hamburg : Design, Technology, Art - the

Convergence of Adjacent Fields

Putting the HER in "HERO": Why We Need More Women in Tech

Sep 2018 — Sep 2018

**HAMBURG** 

FIRESIDE CHAT: Toast to the Art in Artificial Intelligence

http://www.indeed-innovation.com/journal/design-technology-and-art-the-fertility-of-adjacent-fields

Jun 2018 - Jun 2018

**HAMBURG** 

Panel Discussion: Mind the Progress

http://www.mindtheprogress.de/speaker/

May 2018 — May 2018

**BERLIN** 

Ignite Digital BCG for young professionals

I took part in the "Ignite Digital BCG Workshop" on May 10, 2019 in Berlin. Insightful lectures/case studies from Digital BCG were presented.

#### **Awards**

Mar 2015 - Feb 2017

National Science & Technology Scholarship

Full scholarship for graduate programme

Jun 2006 - Mar 2010

National Science & Technology Scholarship

Full scholarship for undergraduate programme

Apr 2004 - Apr 2005

Lee Geon Hee, Samsung CEO Scholarship